# Elisabeth C Gray

elcgray@gmail.com 317-435-1257 http://elisabethgray.me/cv

#### **Profile**

My work experience over the past ten years is based in technology–from service to education to financial tech roles–but my long-term focus is on people, improving civic engagement and political transparency. Academically, I focused my research on media technology's role in conflict, primarily in the MENA and the Balkans. The underlying theme in my work is hinged upon one observation: the tools we use to disseminate information expose base commonalities in our motivations for conflict and peace.

#### **Research Interests**

- · Relationships between technology, society, and conflict
- Role of media in conflict, particularly in:
  - o Bosnia-Herzegovina
  - o Middle East North Africa (MENA)
  - o United States-particularly with regard to racial inequality

### **Papers**

- Never Again? The US Response to Genocide in Bosnia and Rwanda
- Building Fences: Saudi Arabia's Strategy for National Security
- Information Warfare: The Roles of Social Media in Conflict
- Se Va a Poner Feo: The Culture of Violence in Mexico and Its Impact on Development Efforts

## **Projects and Presentations**

Title	Year	Description	
Documentation Domination: How to Build a Knowledge Sharing Culture in 4 Easy Steps	2015	<ul> <li>One of 10 proposals selected by Atlassian panel for the <i>Interact</i> track</li> <li>Full house for the presentation, with over 100 people turned away</li> </ul>	

Social Media and the Arab Uprisings	2015	<ul> <li>Built website using Jekyll to host blog posts on Github</li> <li>Designed and implemented a structured research plan</li> <li>Composed and delivered 14 articles on the topic in blog post format</li> <li>Performed a formative evaluation of the project data (Twitter, Facebook, and Google analytics)</li> </ul>
Israel-Palestine Project	2014	<ul> <li>Led a team of four through a half-semester group project which explored options for conflict resolution in the region of Israel-Palestine</li> <li>Managed and contributed to the composition of a paper and presentation on the subject</li> </ul>
Out of Sight	2005	<ul> <li>Researched homeless outreach programs available in Indianapolis</li> <li>Interviewed outreach professionals as well as individuals experiencing homelessness</li> <li>Collected, edited, and archived audio and video from interviews</li> <li>Presented undergraduate capstone—a video documentary on homeless youth in Indianapolis, Indiana—to a lecture hall of faculty and peers</li> <li>Facilitated a viewing and question-and-answer session on the research, production, and findings of the project</li> <li>Defended research, production, and findings before a faculty panel</li> </ul>

# **Education**

University	Degree	Graduation Year
Arizona State University	Master of Science, Global Technology and Development	2015
Indiana University Purdue University Indianapolis, School of Informatics	<ul> <li>Bachelor of Science, Media Arts and Sciences</li> <li>Concentration, Journalism</li> <li>Minor, French</li> <li>Computer Science certificate coursework</li> </ul>	2005

# Competencies

# **Computer Science**

Skill	Related Tools and Packages	Experience 1=novice 3=advanced
Apple OS	Mac OS Terminal	3
BibTeX	Jekyll-Scholar	3
HTML	Google Web Tools, Atom	3
Markdown	Atom	3
CSS	Google Web Tools, Atom	2
Git	Github	2
JavaScript	Node.js, NPM	2
Ruby	Jekyll, Liquid	2
Windows	Command Prompt	2
Apple iOS	Xcode	1
Continuous integration	Travis CI	1
Data analysis and visualization	IBM SPSS, Google Analytics, Twitter Analytics, <u>TweetTracker</u>	1
Sass	Atom, Chrome DevTools	1
SQL	Sequel Pro	1

## Communication

Skill	Related Tools and Packages	Experience 1=novice 3=advanced
Digital publishing	iWork, Microsoft Word, Adobe: InDesign, Pagemaker	3
English	-	3
Knowledge management	Atlassian Confluence, PBworks, MediaWiki	3
Project management	Trello, Github, Asana, Desk	3
Research	LexisNexis, JSTOR, Google Scholar, Open Access Journals	3
Technical writing	Atom, Google Docs, Github	3

Video editing	Final Cut Pro	3
Customer relationship management	Salesforce, <u>desk.com</u>	2
Database management	Microsoft Excel, FileMaker Pro	2
Digital media creation	iLife, Adobe: Acrobat, Illustrator, Photoshop	2
Educational assessment	NWEA MAP testing	2
French	-	2
Student information administration	PowerSchool	2

## **Work Experience**

#### **Braintree**

#### Knowledge Management Lead; Ops Specialist; Integration Support

Chicago, IL – 2011-Present

- Founded a dedicated documentation team for the creation and maintenance of internal and publicfacing support content
- Managed the design and multi-phase release of a new public documentation structure for Braintree support content: this included the reorganization of existing <u>developer content</u>, the introduction of a server-side reference, and the deployment of a new non-technical support article site
- Co-led initiative to create the first centralized company intranet using Atlassian Confluence
  - Migrated existing content into new structure
  - Managed Confluence user setup and permissions, and plugin installation and updates
  - Designed and led training sessions on new tool, processes, and procedures
  - Authored internal and public-facing content to assist with common questions
- Managed Operations content and process development for the first joint product release as a subsidiary of PayPal
- Created computer image for new hires and provided company-wide technical support prior to the establishment of a dedicated IT team
- Design and implement methods for syncing large repositories of shared content between separate organizations within the company
- Collaborate with cross-organizational teams on technical initiatives to improve documentation content, accessibility, and functionality via iteration planning meetings between multiple team locations
- Liaise with Product and Operations teams to determine new product documentation needs and identify opportunities for collaboration
- Attend product kick-off meetings and disseminating information to stakeholders
- Coordinate with IT team on Confluence version upgrade timelines, creating user permission groups, and setting space permissions

#### **University of Chicago Charter School**

#### Technology Director; Tech Support Specialist

Chicago, IL - 2008-2011

- Organized and facilitated a 1:1 technology program using Apple products for 600 students and staff
  - Designed policy and procedure
  - Managed asset maintenance and distribution
  - Developed and administered training sessions for teachers and students
- Designed class to teach students technical troubleshooting and repair
- Reconciled the technology budget and reduced the technology loss rate on campus from 36% to 3.69% by 2009 and to 0.71% by 2011
- Managed deployment and facilitation of computer-based assessments (e.g. NWEA MAP tests)
- Performed server maintenance

#### **Apple Inc**

#### Mac Genius; Visual Specialist

Chicago, IL & Indianapolis, IN – 2004-2008

- Diagnosed and repaired computer hardware and software issues
- Educated customers on computer maintenance and troubleshooting
- Trained new employees
- Managed software versions and hardware upgrades for front and back of house operations

#### **Gold Wing Touring Association**

#### Media and Marketing Manager

Indianapolis, IN - 2002-2004

- Designed, organized, and edited the non-profit association's monthly magazine
- Negotiated and communicated with advertisers and printers
- Developed marketing, advertising plans, and media for the association

# **Professional Development**

Course	Organization	Year	Status
Jekyll and Github Pages	Udemy	2015	Complete
Management Fundamentals	American Management Association	2015	Complete
SQL	Udemy	2015	Complete
Big Data and Social Physics	edX	2015	In progress

Javascript Udemy 2015 In progre	y 2015   In progress
---------------------------------	----------------------

## Memberships

Title	Organization	Years
Member	Association for Information Science and Technology	2015
Technology Committee	Woodlawn Children's Promise Community Chicago, IL	2009-2011
Technology Educator	Illinois Computing Educators Chicago, IL	2009-2011

### **Conferences and Events**

- Atlassian Summit (2015)
- Write the Docs (2015)
- Chicago Humanities Festival
  - o Hacker, Hoaxer, Whistleblower, Spy with Gabriella Coleman (2015)
  - Dispatches from Dystopia with Kate Brown (2015)
  - Media Against Fascism: From World War II to the Psychedelic Sixties with Fred Turner (2015)
  - o The New Face of Global Activism with Maryam Al-Khawaja (2014)
- PowerSchool University (2010)
- <u>Illinois Computing Educators</u> (2009-2010)

## **Certifications**

- Apple Certified Support Professional (ACSP) 10.5
- Mac OS X Support Essentials v10.5 Certification
- Apple Certified Mac Technician 10.5 (ACMT)